These are some photos of me volunteering in a Cambodian orphanage
هذه بعض الصور من فترة تطوعي في دار للأيتام في كومبوديا
in 2006.
عام 2006.
When these photos were taken,
عندما تم التقاط هذة الصور،
I thought I was doing a really good thing
كنت أعتقد بأنني أفعل شيئًا جيدًا حقًا
and that I was really helping those kids.
وأني كنت حقأ أساعد الأطفال.
I had a lot to learn.
كان لدي الكثير لأتعلمه.
It all started for me when I was 19 years old
بدأ كل هذا عندما كنت في سن 19
and went backpacking through Southeast Asia.
عندما ذهبت أحمل حقيبة ظهر عبر شمال أسيا.
When I reached Cambodia,
عندما وصلت إلى كومبوديا،
I felt uncomfortable being on holiday surrounded by so much poverty
شعرت بعدم الإرتياح كوني في عطلة ومحاطة بكثير من الفقر
and wanted to do something to give back.
أردت أن أفعل شيئًا بالمقابل.
So I visited some orphanages and donated some clothes and books
لذلك زرت بعض دور الأيتام وتبرعت ببعض الملابس والكتب
and some money
وقليل من المال
to help the kids that I met.
لمساعدة الأطفال الذين قابلتهم.
But one of the orphanages I visited was desperately poor.
لكن أحد دور الأيتام التي زرتها كان فقيرا للغاية.
I had never encountered poverty like that before in my life.
لم أصادف فقرًا هكذا من قبل في حياتي.
They didn't have funds for enough food,
لم يكن لديهم نقود لتوفير ما يكفي من الطعام
clean water
أو مياه نضيفة
or medical treatment,
أو عناية طبية،
and the sad little faces on those kids
وقد كانت الوجوه الصغيرة الحزينة لهؤلاء الأطفال
were heartbreaking.
تحطم للقلب.
So I was compelled to do something more to help.
لذا كنت مجبرةً على فعل أكثر من هذا لأساعدهم.
I fund-raised in Australia and returned to Cambodia the following year
جمعت أموالًا في أستراليا ورجعت إلى كومبوديا في السنة التالية
to volunteer at the orphanage for a few months.
لأتطوع في الدار الأيتام لبضعة أشهر.
I taught English and bought water filters and food
درّست اللغة الإنجليزية واشتريت مرشحات المياه والأكل
and took all of the kids to the dentist for the first time in their lives.
وأخذت كل الأطفال إلى طبيب الأسنان لأول مرة في حياتهم.
But over the course of the next year,
لكن في خطتي للعام القادم،
I came to discover that this orphanage that I had been supporting
أتيت لأجد أن دار الأيتام الذي كنت أدعمه
was terribly corrupt.
أصابه الفساد على نحو مريع.
The director had been embezzling every cent donated to the orphanage,
كان المدير يختلس كل سنت يتبرع به لدار الأيتام،
and in my absence, the children were suffering such gross neglect
وفي غيابي، كان الأطفال يعانون من إهمال فظيع
that they were forced to catch mice to feed themselves.
حيث أجبروا على الإمساك بالفئران لإطعام أنفسهم.
I also found out later
واكتشفت لاحقًا
that the director had been physically and sexually abusing the kids.
أن المدير كان يأذيهم جسديًا وجنسيًا.
I couldn't bring myself to turn my back on children
لم أستطع أن أضغط على نفسي لأدير ظهري للأطفال
who I had come to know and care about
الذين أتيت لأعرفهم وأهتم بهم
and return to my life in Australia.
وبعد ذلك أعود إلى حياتي في أستراليا.
So I worked with a local team and the local authorities
لذلك عملت مع فريق محلي والسلطات المحلية
to set up a new orphanage and rescue the kids
لبناء دار أيتام جديد وإنقاذ الأطفال
to give them a safe new home.
كي أمنحهم منزلًا آمنًا جديدًا.
But this is where my story takes another unexpected turn.
ومن هنا أخذت قصتي منحنًا غير متوقع آخر.
As I adjusted to my new life running an orphanage in Cambodia,
حيث عدلت حياتي كي أدير دارً للأيتام في كومبوديا،
(Khmer) I learned to speak Khmer fluently,
(الخميرية) تعلمت التحدث بالخميرية بطلاقة،
which means that I learned to speak the Khmer language fluently.
وهذا يعني أني تعلمت التحدث باللغة الخميرية بطلاقة.
And when I could communicate properly with the kids,
وعندما بدأت التواصل مع الأطفال بصورة صحيحة،
I began to uncover some strange things.
بدأت أكشف النقاب عن أشياء غريبة.
Most of the children we had removed from the orphanage
معضم الأطفال الذين أخرجناهم من الدار الأيتام
were not, in fact, orphans at all.
في الواقع لم يكونوا أيتامًا.
They had parents,
كان لديهم والدان،
and the few that were orphaned had other living relatives,
وقليل من الذين كانوا أيتامًا كان لديهم أقرباء على قيد الحياة،
like grandparents and aunties and uncles
مثل الأجداد والعمات والأعمام
and other siblings.
وأشقاء آخرين.
So why were these children living in an orphanage
إذن لماذا يعيش هؤلاء الأطفال في دار للأيتام
when they weren't orphans?
إذا لم يكونوا أيتاما؟
Since 2005, the number of orphanages in Cambodia
منذ عام 2005 ازداد عدد دور الأيتام في كومبوديا
has risen by 75 percent,
بنسبة 75 بالمئة،
and the number of children living in Cambodian orphanages
كما تضاعف عدد الأطفال الذين يعيشون في دور الأيتام في كومبوديا
has nearly doubled,
إلى الضعف تقريبًا،
despite the fact
على الرغم من حقيقة
that the vast majority of children living in these orphanages
أن الأغلبية الساحقة من الأطفال الذين يعيشون في دور الأيتام هذه
are not orphans in the traditional sense.
لم يكونوا أيتامًا كما هو متعارف عليه.
They're children from poor families.
بل كانوا أطفالًا من أسر فقيرة.
So if the vast majority of children living in orphanages
لذا إن كانت الأغلبية الساحقة من الأطفال الذين يعيشون في الدور
are not orphans,
ليسوا أيتامًا،
then the term "orphanage"
إذن مصطلح "دور أيتام"
is really just a euphemistic name for a residential care institution.
هو مجرد اسم تلطيفي لمؤسسة رعاية سكنية.
These institutions go by other names as well,
تعمل هذه المؤسسات تحت مسميات أخرى أيضًا،
like "shelters," "safe houses," "children's homes," "children's villages,"
مثل "الملاجىء" أو "المنازل الآمنة" أو "منازل الأطفال" أو "قرى الأطفال"
even "boarding schools."
حتى "مدارس داخلية."
And this problem is not just confined to Cambodia.
وهذه المشكلة ليست مقتصرة على كومبوديا فقط.
This map shows some of the countries that have seen a dramatic increase
تظهر هذه الخريطة بعض الدول التي شهدت زيادة مضطردة
in the numbers of residential care institutions
في عدد مؤسسات الرعايه السكنية
and the numbers of children being institutionalized.
وعدد الأطفال الذين تم استيعابهم فيها.
In Uganda, for example,
في يوغندا على سبيل المثال
the number of children living in institutions
عدد الأطفال الذين يعيشون في هذه المؤسسات
has increased by more than 1,600 percent since 1992.
ازداد بنسبة 16000 بالمئة منذ عام 1992
And the problems posed by putting kids into institutions
والمشكلة التي طرأت نتيجة وضع الأطفال في المؤسسات
don't just pertain to the corrupt and abusive institutions
لا تتعلق فقط بالفساد والمؤسسات المسيئة
like the one that I rescued the kids from.
مثل المؤسسة التي أنقذت الأطفال منها.
The problems are with all forms of residential care.
المشكلة موجودة في كل أنواع العناية السكنية.
Over 60 years of international research has shown us
أكثر من 60 عاما من الأبحاث الدولية بينت لنا
that children who grow up in institutions,
أن الاطفال الذين يكبرون في المؤسسات،
even the very best institutions,
حتى أفضل المؤسسات،
are at serious risk of developing mental illnesses,
هم عرضة للإصابة بأمراض نفسية،
attachment disorders,
واضطرابات في التواصل،
growth and speech delays,
وتأخر في النمو والتكلم،
and many will struggle with an inability to reintegrate
وكثير منهم سيعانون من عدم القدرة على العودة
back into society later in life
للاندماج مع المجتمع لاحقًا في حياتهم
and form healthy relationships as adults.
وتكوين علاقات صحيّة كبالغين.
These kids grow up without any model of family
هؤلاء الأطفال يكبرون بمعزل عن أي نموذج أو عائلة
or of what good parenting looks like,
أو كيف تبدو الأبوة أو الأمومة الجيدة،
so they then can struggle to parent their own children.
لذلك سيعانون في الإعتناء بأطفالهم.
So if you institutionalize large numbers of children,
لذا إذا استوعبت عدداً كبيراً من الأطفال،
it will affect not only this generation,
فهذا لن يؤثر على الجيل الحالي فقط،
but also the generations to come.
بل الجيل القادم أيضاً.
We've learned these lessons before in Australia.
تعلمنا هذه الدروس من قبل في أستراليا.
It's what happened to our "Stolen Generations,"
هذا ما حدث "لجيلنا الضائع،"
the indigenous children who were removed from their families
السكان الأصلييون من الأطفال الذين فرّق بينهم وبين عوائلهم
with the belief that we could do a better job
مع الاعتقاد بأننا نستطيع فعل شيء أفضل
of raising their children.
عن طريق تربية أطفالهم.
Just imagine for a moment
فقط تخيل لدقيقة
what residential care would be like for a child.
ما ستكون عليه الرعاية السكنية لطفل.
Firstly, you have a constant rotation of caregivers,
أولًا، لديك جولات ثابتة لمقدمي الرعاية،
with somebody new coming on to the shift every eight hours.
مع شخص جديد يأتي كل ثمان ساعات.
And then on top of that you have a steady stream of visitors
وعلى رأس كل هذا لديك تدفق ثابت للزوار
and volunteers coming in,
والمتطوعين الزائرين،
showering you in the love and affection you're craving
ليغسلونكَ بالحب والمودة التي أردتها
and then leaving again,
وبعدها يتركوكَ مرة أخرى،
evoking all of those feelings of abandonment,
ثائرًا كل أحاسيس الإهمال هذه،
and proving again and again
ويثبتون ذلك مرة تلو الأخرى
that you are not worthy of being loved.
بأنك لا تستحق أن تكون محبوباً.
We don't have orphanages in Australia, the USA, the UK anymore,
لم يعد لدينا دور للأيتام في أستراليا أو أمريكا أو المملكة المتحدة،
and for a very good reason:
ولسبب جيد جيدًا:
one study has shown that young adults raised in institutions
أظهرت إحدى الأبحاث بأن المراهقين الذين تربوا في مؤسسات
are 10 times more likely to fall into sex work than their peers,
أكثر عرضة بعشرة مرات للانخراط في أعمال جنسية من نظرائهم،
40 times more likely to have a criminal record,
أكثر عرضة 40 مرة بأن يكون لهم سجل جنائي،
and 500 times more likely
أكثر عرضة 500 مرة
to take their own lives.
بأن يزهقوا أرواحهم.
There are an estimated eight million children around the world
هناك ما يقارب من ثمانية مليون طفل في جميع أنحاء العالم
living in institutions like orphanages,
يعيشون في مؤسسات مماثلة لدور الأيتام،
despite the fact that around 80 percent of them are not orphans.
رغم أن 80 بالمئة منهم ليسوا أيتامًا.
Most have families who could be caring for them
لذا الأغلبية منهم عوائل من الممكن أن تعتني بهم
if they had the right support.
لو توفّر لهم الدعم الكافي.
But for me,
لكن بالنسبة لي،
the most shocking thing of all to realize
كان أكثر شيء مثير للصدمة اكتشافه
is what's contributing to this boom
هو ما يساهم في هذه الاتساع
in the unnecessary institutionalization of so many children:
هو الاسيتيعاب غير الضروري للعديد من الأطفال.
it's us --
أي نحن
the tourists, the volunteers
السائحون والمتطوعون
and the donors.
والجهات الواهبة.
It's the well-meaning support from people like me back in 2006,
هو الدعم بالنية الحسنة من أشخاص مثلي في 2006
who visit these children and volunteer and donate,
الذين زاروا هؤلاء الأطفال وتطوعوا ووهبوا،
who are unwittingly fueling an industry that exploits children
والذين يغذون بغير قصد هذه الصناعة التي تستغل الأطفال
and tears families apart.
وتفرّق العوائل عن بعضهم البعض.
It's really no coincidence that these institutions are largely set up
ليس من الصدفة أن هذه المؤسسات أنشئت على نحو كبير
in areas where tourists can most easily be lured in
في أماكن يصل إليها السائحون بسهولة
to visit and volunteer in exchange for donations.
للزيارة والتبرع.
Of the 600 so-called orphanages in Nepal,
من بين 600 من ما يسمى بدور الأيتام في نيبال،
over 90 percent of them are located in the most popular tourist hotspots.
أكثر من 90 بالمئة منها تقع في المناطق التي يرتادها السياح بكثرة.
The cold, hard truth is,
الحقيقة الباردة والصعبة هي،
the more money that floods in in support of these institutions,
كلما زادت الأموال التي تفيض لدعم هذه المؤسسات،
the more institutions open
كلما افتتحت المزيد من هذه المؤسسات
and the more children are removed from their families
وكلما أبعد المزيد من الأطفال عن أسرهم
to fill their beds.
لملء أسرة هذه المؤسسات.
It's just the laws of supply and demand.
إنها مجرد قوانين العرض والطلب.
I had to learn all of these lessons the hard way,
كان يجب علي أن أتعلم كل هذه الدروس بالطريقة الصعبة،
after I had already set up an orphanage in Cambodia.
بعد أن أنشأت دارًا للأيتام في كومبوديا.
I had to eat a big piece of humble pie to admit
كان يجب أن أعترف بشكل إجباري
that I had made a mistake
بأني اقترفت خطأً
and inadvertently become a part of the problem.
وأصبحت بدون قصد جزءًا من المشكلة.
I had been an orphanage tourist,
لقد كنت زائرةً لدور الأيتام،
a voluntourist.
زائرةً متطوعةً.
I then set up my own orphanage and facilitated orphanage tourism
أسست بعدها داري الخاصة للأيتام وساهمت في سياحة دور الأيتام
in order to generate funds for my orphanage,
من أجل الحصول على المال لدار الأيتام الخاص بي،
before I knew better.
قبل أن أعرف على نحو أفضل.
What I came to learn
ما تعلمته لاحقًا
is that no matter how good my orphanage was,
أنه لا يهم كيف كان دار الأيتام الخاص بي جيدا،
it was never going to give those kids what they really needed:
لأنه سوف لن يمنح أولئك الأطفال ما يحتاجونه حقًا
their families.
وهو عوائلهم.
I know that it can feel incredibly depressing
أعلم بأن هذا قد يشعركم بكآبة لا تصدق
to learn that helping vulnerable children and overcoming poverty
أن نعلم بأن مساعدة الأطفال الضعفاء والتغلب على الفقر
is not as simple as we've all been led to believe it should be.
ليس أمرًا سهلا كما اعتقدنا دومًا.
But thankfully, there is a solution.
لكن لحسن الحظ، هناك حل.
These problems are reversible and preventable,
هذه المشاكل يمكن عكسها ومنع حدوثها،
and when we know better,
وعندما نعرف على نحو أفضل،
we can do better.
يمكننا فعل شيء أفضل.
The organization that I run today,
المؤسسة التي أديرها حاليًا،
the Cambodian Children's Trust,
ثقة أطفال كومبوديا،
is no longer an orphanage.
لم تعد دارًا للأيتام.
In 2012, we changed the model in favor of family-based care.
في العام 2012، قمنا بتغيير النموذج لصالح العناية الأسرية.
I now lead an amazing team of Cambodian social workers,
وحاليا أدير فريقًا مدهشًا من الأخصائيين الاجتماعيين الكومبوديين،
nurses and teachers.
ممرضات ومعلمين.
Together, we work within communities
معا، نعمل داخل المجتمعات
to untangle a complex web of social issues
لفك شبكة معقدة من القضايا الاجتماعية
and help Cambodian families escape poverty.
ولمساعدة العوائل الكومبودية في النجاة من الفقر.
Our primary focus is on preventing some of the most vulnerable families
تركيزنا الأساسي هو وقاية بعض الأسر الأكثر ضعفَا
in our community
في مجتمعاتنا
from being separated in the first place.
من الانفصال في المقام الأول.
But in cases where it's not possible
لكن في بعض الحالات عندما لا يمكن
for a child to live with its biological family,
للطفل أن يعيش مع عائلته البيولوجية،
we support them in foster care.
ندعمهم من خلال الرعاية المعززة.
Family-based care is always better
الرعاية الأسرية هي دائما الأفضل
than placing a child in an institution.
من وضع الطفل في مؤسسة.
Do you remember that first photo that I showed you before?
هل تتذكرون أول صورة عرضتها عليكم في البداية؟
See that girl who is just about to catch the ball?
هل ترون هذه الفتاة التي على وشك أن تلتقط الكرة؟
Her name is Torn
تدعى تورن
She's a strong, brave and fiercely intelligent girl.
إنها فتاة قوية وشجاعة ومتقدة الذكاء.
But in 2006, when I first met her
لكن في العام 2006 عندما قابلتها لأول مرة
living in that corrupt and abusive orphanage,
كانت تعيش في دار أيتام فاسدة ومسيئة،
she had never been to school.
لم تذهب للمدرسة قط.
She was suffering terrible neglect,
كانت تعاني من إهمال رهيب،
and she yearned desperately
وتتوق بيأس
for the warmth and love of her mother.
لدفء وحب والدتها.
But this is a photo of Torn today with her family.
لكن هذه هي صورة تورن اليوم مع عائلتها.
Her mother now has a secure job,
لدا والدتها اليوم وظيفة آمنة،
her siblings are doing well in high school
وأشقاؤها يبلون حسنصا في المدارس العليا
and she is just about to finish her nursing degree at university.
وهي على وشك الحصول على شهادة التمريض في الجامعة.
For Torn's family --
بالنسبة لعائلة تورن
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
for Torn's family,
بالنسبة لعائلة تورن،
the cycle of poverty has been broken.
تحطمت دائرة الفقر.
The family-based care model that we have developed at CCT
نموذج الرعاية الاسرية التي قمنا بتطويرها في مؤسسة ثقة اطفال كومبوديا
has been so successful,
نجحت كثيرًا.
that it's now being put forward by UNICEF Cambodia
والتى تتقدم إلى الأمام برعاية يونسيف كومبودبا
and the Cambodian government
والحكومة الكومبودية
as a national solution to keep children in families.
كحل وطني لإبقاء الأطفال مع عوائلهم.
And one of the best --
وواحدة من الأفضل
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And one of the best ways that you can help to solve this problem
وواحدة من أفضل الطرق التي يمكن من خلالها حل المشكلة
is by giving these eight million children a voice
هو بإعطاء هؤلاء الثمانية ملايين طفل صوتًا
and become an advocate for family-based care.
وأن تصبح داعية للرعاية الأسرية.
If we work together to raise awareness,
إذا ما عملنا معًا لزيادة الوعي،
we can make sure the world knows
يمكننا أن نتأكد من أن العالم يعلم
that we need to put an end to the unnecessary institutionalization
بأننا نحتاج إلى وضع نهاية للمأساة غير الضرورية
of vulnerable children.
التي يتعرض لها الأطفال الضعفاء.
How do we achieve that?
كيف يمكننا تحيق هذا؟
By redirecting our support and our donations
من خلال إعادة توجيه دعمنا وعطائنا
away from orphanages and residential care institutions
بعيدًا عن دور الأيتام ومؤسسسات الرعاية الصحية
towards organizations that are committed to keeping children in families.
بل تجاه المنظمات الملتزمة بإبقاء الأطفال مع عوائلهم.
I believe we can make this happen in our lifetime,
أؤمن بأننا نستطيع فعل ذلك في عصرنا هذا،
and as a result, we will see developing communities thrive
ونتجية لذلك، سنرى أن المجتمعات البدائية تزدهر
and ensure that vulnerable children everywhere
ونضمن بأن الاطفال الضعفاء في كل مكان
have what all children need and deserve:
لديهم كل ما يحتاجه ويستحقه الأطفال
a family.
ألا وهو العائلة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
تصفيق